A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources, 1999-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- I. Correspondence and subject files, 1999-2010 (bulk 2006-2010)., 27.22 cu. ft. (30 boxes)
  - Assigned state agencies, 1999-2010., 10.35 cu. ft. (11 boxes)
    - Department of Conservation and Recreation, 2004-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Department of Conservation and Recreation. The mission of the Department of Conservation and Recreation is to "conserve, protect, and enhance their lands and improve the quality of the Chesapeake Bay and our rivers and streams, promotes the stewardship and enjoyment of natural, cultural and outdoor recreational resources, and insures the safety of Virginia's dams." Notable projects documented in this series include the Chesapeake Bay Program, the Dam Safety Program, the Land Conservation Tax Credit, and the Water Quality Improvement Fund.
      - Director/Appointees, 2006-2009. (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - General Correspondence, 2006-2009. (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Agriculture Practices, 2006. (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Brumley Mountain Tract, 2005. (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Captain John Smith Water Trail, 2006. (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Agriculture Champion, 2007-2009. (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Bay Health, 2006-2008. (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Captain John Smith Water Trail, 2006. (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Chesapeake 2000 Agreement, 2006. (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Citizen Advisory Committee, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Congress, 2006-2009. (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee, 2006-2007. (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2006. (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Chesapeake Bay Executive Order, 2009. (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Chesapeake Bay Executive Order, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: EPA Region III, 2006. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Federal Reauthorization Legislation, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Government Accountability Office, 2005. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Implementation Committee, 2006-2009. (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Implementation Committee, 2006-2009. (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Inspector General, 2007. (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Management Board, 2008-2009. (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Nitrogen Gap, 2006-2007. (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee, 2006. (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2007. (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Principals' Staff Committee Meeting Materials, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Reorganization, 2007-2008. (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Scientific and Technical Advisory Committee, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Strategic Implementation Plan, 2006-2008. (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Two Year Milestones, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Virginia TMDL Stakeholder Advisory Group, 2009. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Virginia TMDL Stakeholder Advisory Group, 2009. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Chesapeake Bay Program: Water Stewardship, 2007-2009. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission: General, 2006. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission Meeting, 2009. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission Meeting, 2009. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission Meeting, 2008. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission Meeting, 2007. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission, 2006-2007. (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Chesapeake Bay Commission Meeting, 2006. (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Crow's Nest, 2005-2007. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Dam Safety Program, 2005-2006. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Dam Safety Program: T. Nelson Elliott, 2007. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Dam Safety Program: Jolly Pond Road, 2007. (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Dame Safety Program: Lake of the Woods, 2007-2009. (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Dam Safety Program: Lake of the Woods, 2007-2009. (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Dam Safety Program: Springhill Lake, 2007. (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Explore Park, 2005-2008. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - High Bridge Rails to Trails, 2004-2006. (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Land Conservation Tax Credit, 2005. (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Land Conservation Tax Credit: Meeting with Delegate Ware, 2005. (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Land Conservation Tax Credit, 2005. (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Land Conservation Tax Credit, 2005. (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Land Conservation Tax Credit Subcommittees, 2005. (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Non-Point Source Pollution Education Materials, 2006. (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Non-Point Source Pollution Education Materials, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Occoneechee State Park, 2007-2008. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Public Water Access, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - State Parks: Issues, 2005-2006. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Stewardship Virginia Program, 2006-2009. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Stormwater, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Stormwater: Pervious Concrete, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Stormwater regulations, 2009. (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Outdoors Foundation, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Virginia Outdoors Foundation: Cox Chapel Prison Site, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Virginia Outdoors Foundation: The Mary Moody Northern Endowment, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Water Quality Improvement Fund, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Water Quality Improvement Fund: Clean Fuels Project, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Water Quality Improvement Fund: VRA Financing, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Wintergreen Land Conservation Project, 2008. (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Department of Environmental Quality 1999-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Department of Environmental Quality. The Department is "dedicated to protecting Virginia's environment and promoting the health and well-being of the citizens of the Commonwealth. We accomplish this by planning and implementing environmental programs, and by resolving issues efficiently, openly, fairly and consistently." Notable projects documented in this series include the Camden County landfill, the North Anna Nuclear Power Plant, the proposed King William Reservoir, and water quality improvements, among others.
      - Director, 2006-2009. (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - General Correspondence, 2006-2009. (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - General Correspondence, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Environmental Impact Reviews, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Environmental Stewardship Awards, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Environmental Stewardship Awards, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund: Gubernatorial Appointee, 2005-2006. (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Air: Biofuels, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Air: Biofuels-DRI Incorporated, 2005-2006. (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Air: Dominion North Anna Unit 3 Environmental Briefing, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Air: Interstate Air Quality Council, 2005-2008. (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - Air: The Climate Registry, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - Air: Mercury Assessment, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - Air: Mirant, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - Air: Mirant, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - Air: Metropolitan Washington Air Quality Committee, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - Air: Ozone Transport Commission-Commonwealth's Gubernatorial Representative, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 32)
      - Environmental Enhancement: State Environmental Review Process, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - Hawk's Nest Golf Course-Virginia Emergency Fuel Storage, 2004-2006. (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - Special: Highland County Wind Farm, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 35)
      - Special: Highland County Wind Farm, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - Special: Olin Corporation NRDA Funding and Participation Agreement, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 37)
      - Waste: Biosolids, undated. (Box 20, Folder 38)
      - Waste: Blue Plains Wastewater Treatment Plant, 2006-2007. (Box 20, Folder 39)
      - Waste: Brownfields, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 40)
      - Waste: Camden County (Black Bear) Landfill, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 41)
      - Waste: Camden County (Black Bear) Landfill, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Waste: Galaxy/Spectron Superfund Site, Elkton, MD, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Waste: Hidden Lane Landfill Super Fund Site, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Waste: Poultry Litter Stakeholder Group, 2007-2008. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Waste: Poultry Litter Stakeholder Group, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Waste: Poultry Litter Stakeholder Group, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Waste: Poultry Litter Stakeholder Group-Draft Legislation, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Waste: Septic System Financing Initiative, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Waste: Solid Waste, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Waste: Tipping Fees, undated. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Waste: Uniform Environmental Covenants Act, 2005-2006. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Waste: Uniform Environmental Covenants Act, 2004. (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Waste: Waste-to-Energy, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Water: CSO, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Water: Endocrine Disrupting Compound, 2008. (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Fairfax County Parkway, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Water: Fish Kills, 2006-2007. (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Water: Fish Kills, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Water: King William Reservoir, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Water: King William Reservoir Project Decision Memorandum, 2003-2004. (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Water: King William Reservoir, undated. (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - Water: Final Recommended Record of Decision of the District Commander, 2001. (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - Water: King William Reservoir Project Final Wetland Mitigation Plan, 1999. (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Water: King William County Reservoir Project Final Wetland Mitigation Plan, 1999. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Board Consolidation, 2007. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Water: No Discharge Zones, 2007-2009. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Water: North Anna Nuclear Power Plant and Lake Anna Jurisdictional Issues, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Water: Nutrient Trading, 2005-2007. (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Water: Product Preauthorization Guidelines for Use of CIAgent, 2007. (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Water: Section 404 Designation, 2006-2007. (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Water: Study Concerning Coordination of Water Quality Programs, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Water: Total Maximum Daily Loads, 2004-2006. (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Water: Virginia Pollutant Discharge Elimination System-Town of Craigsville, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Water: Virginia Water Protection Permit-Wetlands Monitoring, Christopher Newport University, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Water: Virginia Water Protection Permit-Wetlands Program, 2006-2007. (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Water: Water Quality Improvement Fund-Sewage Treatment Plant Funding, 2006-2008. (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Water: Water Reuse Regulations, 2007. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2000-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Department of Game and Inland Fisheries. The Department's mission is "to manage Virginia's wildlife and inland fish to maintain optimum populations of all species to serve the needs of the Commonwealth; To provide opportunity for all to enjoy wildlife, inland fish, boating and related outdoor recreation and to work diligently to safeguard the rights of the people to hunt, fish and harvest game as provided for in the Constitution of Virginia; To promote safety for persons and property in connection with boating, hunting and fishing; To provide educational outreach programs and materials that foster an awareness of and appreciation for Virginia's fish and wildlife resources, their habitats, and hunting, fishing, and boating opportunities." Notable events documented in this series include the controversy over the trip to Africa taken by a number of employees of the Department of Game and Inland Fisheries and potential donations of land by private individuals.
      - Board of Directors Code of Ethics and Conduct, 2005. (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Board of Directors General Policies, 2005. (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Board of Directors Governance Manual, 2005. (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Board Meeting Materials, 2006-2007. (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Board Meeting Materials, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - Board Meeting Materials, 2006. (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Director, 2006-2009. (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - General Correspondence, 2006-2009. (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Controversy: Correspondence, 2004-2005. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Controversy: Correspondence, 2004-2005. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Controversy: Exhibits, 2005. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Controversy: Exhibits, 2005. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Controversy: Audit, 2004-2005. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Controversy, 2003-2006. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Controversy, 2005. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Controversy, 2004-2006. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Goodall Property, 2005-2008. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Goodall Property, 2000-2005. (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Lands along the Rappahannock and Rapidan Rivers, 2005. (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Philpott 216 Study, 2006-2009. (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Sunday Hunting Survey, 2007. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Department of Historic Resources, 2004-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Department of Historic Resources. The Department's mission is "to foster, encourage, and support the identification, stewardship, and use of Virginia's significant historic, architectural, archaeological and cultural resources." Primarily contains information relating to historic preservation of various properties throughout Virginia.
      - Director/Appointees, 2006-2007. (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - General Correspondence, 2005-2009. (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Clermont Farm, 2004-2005. (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Federal Historic Tax Credit, 2006-2007. (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Oakwood Cemetery, 2006-2009. (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2006-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Virginia Museum of Natural History. The Museum's mission is "to interpret Virginia's natural heritage within a global context in ways that are relevant to all citizens of the Commonwealth."
      - Executive Director, 2006-2009. (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - General Correspondence, 2006. (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Trout in the Classrooms, 2007. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Marine Resources Commission, 1999-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Virginia Marine Resources Commission. The Commission "serves as stewards of Virginia's marine and aquatic resources, and protectors of its tidal waters and homelands, for present and future generations." Notable projects documented in this series include the proposal to introduce non-native oysters into the Chesapeake Bay and the state of commercial menhaden harvesting in the Chesapeake Bay.
      - Commissioner/Appointees, 2006-2007. (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - General Correspondence, 2006-2009. (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Agreement between VMRC and Maryland Department of Natural Resources: License Reciprocity, 2008. (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - Aquaculture: Protected Waters, 2006. (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - Aquaculture: Protected Waters, 2006. (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Aquaculture: Protected Waters, 2006. (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Aquaculture: Protected Waters, 2007. (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - Blue Catfish, 2008-2009. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Blue Crab Fishery Management Plan, 2007. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Blue Crabs, 2008. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Blue Crabs, 2007-2009. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Blue Crabs, 2006-2009. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Blue Crabs, 2007-2009. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Blue Ribbon Oyster Panel, 2006-2008. (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Blue Ribbon Oyster Panel, 2006. (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Blue Ribbon Oyster Panel, 2006-2007. (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Blue Ribbon Oyster Panel, 2005-2006. (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Blue Ribbon Oyster Panel, 2006-2007. (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Oyster Restoration in Chesapeake Bay Including the Use of a Native and/or Nonnative Oyster, volume 1, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Oyster Restoration in Chesapeake Bay Including the Use of a Native and/or Nonnative Oyster, volume 2, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Oyster Restoration in Chesapeake Bay Including the Use of a Native and/or Nonnative Oyster, volume 3, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Oyster Restoration in Chesapeake Bay Including the Use of a Native and/or Nonnative Oyster, volume 4, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Final Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement for Oyster Restoration in Chesapeake Bay Including the Use of a Native and/or Nonnative Oyster, volume 4, 2009. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2002-2003. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2001-2002. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2003. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2003. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2001-2003. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2005. (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2004-2005. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2003-2006. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2008-2009. (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2005. (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2006-2007. (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2008-2009. (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Chesapeake Bay Oyster Environmental Impact Statement, 2007-2008. (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Horseshoe crabs, 2005-2006. (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Horseshoe crabs, 2006. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Menhaden: ASMFC, 2006-2009. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Menhaden Cap Correspondence, 2006. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Menhaden Cap Correspondence, 2005-2006. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Management plan, 2006. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Annual Reviews, 2000-2005. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Stock Assessment, 2004. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Stock Assessment, 1999-2004. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Minutes, 2004-2005. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation: Minutes, 2004-2005. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation, 2004-2008. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Menhaden Cap Documentation, 2004. (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Menhaden: CBF Proposal, 2007. (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Menhaden: Chichester, 2006-2007. (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Menhaden: Corbin Personal Notes, 2006. (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Menhaden: VMRC, 2007. (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Menhaden: Harvest Data, 2006-2008. (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Menhaden Industry, 2005-2006. (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Menhaden Industry, 2004. (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Menhaden Industry, 2004. (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Menhaden: Legislation, 2005-2006. (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Menhaden Memorandum of Understanding: Omega and Virginia, 2006. (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Menhaden: Omega Reedville Discharge Permit, 2005-2006. (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Menhaden Proclamation, 2006. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Menhaden: Socio-economic Study, 2007. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Menhaden Cap Research, 2006. (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Native Oysters: Reeftek Design, 2006. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Subaqueous Land, undated. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Natural Gas: Hampton Roads Crossing, 2008. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Council on Indians, 2006-2009.
      Contains correspondence and subject files of the Virginia Council on Indians. The Council's mission is "to serve as the advisory board to the Commonwealth on issues affecting the Virginia Indians and to advocate for the education of the public regarding the past and present Indians of Virginia."
      - Federal Recognition, 2007. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - General Correspondence, 2006-2009. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Environmental organizations, 2002-2007., .35 cu. ft. (1 box)
    Contains correspondence and accompanying material mailed to the Secretary of Natural Resources by various environmental organizations. The organizations include the Chesapeake Bay Foundation, The Nature Conservancy, and the Virginia Seafood Council, among many others.
    - Albemarle-Pamlico Sound Estuary Program, 2005-2006. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - American Rivers, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Chesapeake Bay Foundation, 2005-2006. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Conservation Partners, 2006-2007. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Dan River Basin Association, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - The Nature Conservancy, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Natural Resources Partnership, 2005. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 2007. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Sea Grant, 2005-2006. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Southeast Rural Community Assistance Project, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Trust for Public Land, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Council of Trout Unlimited, 2007. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 2006-2007. (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Seafood Council, 2002-2006. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Governor-related, 2006-2009., .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)